energiseforlife.com 2006-05-13

# Energise for Life: Privacy Policy

**We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy.** The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this web site.

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We will only use the information that we collect about you lawfully (in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998). 

We collect information about you for 2 reasons: firstly, to process your order and second, to provide you with the best possible service. We will not e-mail you in the future unless you have given us your consent. 

We will also give you the chance to refuse any marketing email from us or from another trader in the future. 

The type of information we will collect about you includes:

> \- your name   
>  \- address   
>  \- phone number   
>  \- email address   
>  \- credit/debit card details

We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent. The information we hold will be accurate and up to date. You can check the information that we hold about you by emailing us. If you find any inaccuracies we will delete or correct it promptly. 

The personal information which we hold will be held securely in accordance with our internal security policy and the law. 

If we intend to transfer your information outside the EEA (European Economic Area) we will always obtain your consent first. 

**Cookies/ IP Address**

We may use technology to track the patterns of behaviour of visitors to our site. This can include using a "cookie" which would be stored on your browser. You can usually modify your browser to prevent this happening. The information collected in this way can be used to identify you unless you modify your browser settings. We also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information.

Our site uses cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. We use cookies to identify you so we can retrieve your information so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site.

**Contact/Personal Information**

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information, like their name and email address, and unique identifiers. We use customer contact information from the registration form to send the user information about our company. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary if they have subscribed to the mail list. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings by choosing to un-subscribe. Unique identifiers are collected to verify the user's identity and for use in our record system.

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information and unique identifiers. Contact information from the order form is used to send orders and information about our company to our customers. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings. Unique identifiers are collected from Web site visitors to verify the user's identity and for use as account numbers in our record system.

**Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. All data is protected using the most advanced methods available. We do not store financial information like credit card numbers or personal information like social security numbers on this site.

**Un-Subscribe**

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive mail list messages.

 \- You can send email to us by visiting the [Contact Page](http://www.energiseforlife.com/ccp51/cgi-bin/cp-app.cgi?cur=&usr=51F3069085&rnd=227221&rrc=N&affl=&cip=210.84.45.221&act=&aff=&pg=contact)

 \- You can visit the Mail List Page to [un-subscribe](http://www.energiseforlife.com/ccp51/cgi-bin/cp-app.cgi?cur=&usr=51F3069085&rnd=227221&rrc=N&affl=&cip=210.84.45.221&act=&aff=&pg=maillist)

**Correct/Update**

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. You can send email to us by visiting [Contact Page](http://www.energiseforlife.com/ccp51/cgi-bin/cp-app.cgi?cur=&usr=51F3069085&rnd=227221&rrc=N&affl=&cip=210.84.45.221&act=&aff=&pg=contact)

 _This site may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites._

**Notice**

The information on this website is for informational and educational purposes only. It is not an attempt by the writers or publisher to diagnose or prescribe, nor should it be construed to be such. Readers are hereby encouraged to consult with a licensed health care professional concerning the information presented, which has been received from sources deemed reliable, but no guarantees, expressed or implied, can be made regarding the accuracy of same. Therefore, readers are also encouraged to verify for themselves and to their own satisfaction the accuracy of all reports, recommendations, conclusions, comments, opinions, or anything else published herein before making any kind of decisions based upon what they have read. If you have a medical condition, please consult your medical practitioner.
